## Richard (Arcy) Douglass

5833 SE 22nd Ave Portland, Oregon 97202 503.234.6151 arcydouglass@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/arcydouglass/

### Skill Summary

More than 10 years of experience as an architecture and interior design Project Manager, including delivering complex projects on time and on budget from a wide variety of timescales from a few weeks to several years. Whether it's designing high-end retail space at a Las Vegas casino or organizing artists for a conference, I enjoy collaborating with a team to identify and develop the best approaches to meet client needs and enhance creativity.

#### Education

University of Southern California 1997 Los Angeles, CA Bachelors of Architecture, a five-year professional degree

#### Experience

Instructor, Applied Craft and Design (ACD) 2011 - Present
MFA program, Portland, Oregon
The class develops Project Management skills asking students to:

- Identify and develop core project ideas
- Promote project communication and presentation skills
- Improve critical thinking

Independent Project Manager
Portland, Oregon

2003 - Present

- Identified, produced, and presented work for more than 15
   Visual Art exhibitions
- Produced more than 30 written essays on contemporary art

Senior Project Architect/Manager 2000-2002
Easton-Moss, New York
Private residences on the East Coast

Freelance Architect 1999-2000 Gensler & Adam Tihany, New York

Project Architect/Designer 1997-1999
Marnell Corrao Associates, Las Vegas
Selected projects: Rio Suites, Davidoff Retail Store

#### Certifications

Licensed Architect in the State of New York
National Council of Architectural Registration Boards

#### Recent Projects

Ten Thousand Things February 2012 PCC Sylvania, Portland, Oregon An exhibition of an ever changing visual field based on a complex

• Delivered project on time and budget

mathematical system.

• Researched and developed the technical requirements for the project

# Projects

Donald Judd Delegated Fabrication: History, Practice, Issues and Implications

Portland, Oregon

Co-organized an academic conference on the work of American artist and architect Donald Judd that took place at the University of Oregon in Portland in April 2010.

- Organized and delivered a complex multi-year project
- ullet Developed long term and short term project goals
- Led successful pitches for grants and sponsorship support
- Led monthly project status meetings

Honors and Awards Regional Arts and Culture Council Project Grant

2009